hello and welcome back to another
episode of hermitcraft we are on episode
4 and things are moving very very
quickly so what I've been up to is quite
a lot of work and preparation I mean the
most important thing that I've done is
I've made Professor big a proper home
instead of just standing on the floor
here and what he's proven to me is that
he's actually some sort of deity as he's
floating
he can fly I know parrots can normally
fly but he can fly without flying well
done Professor beak you win and over
here in the passive Farm room I
retrofitted the bone meal Farm into an
XP farm and I've been letting this tick
over until all of this fills up I've no
idea how much xp is stored in here
oh my goodness 43 levels instantly just
from letting that tick away that is
really really nice okay I probably
shouldn't have done that well this one
is ticking away as it as it goes so
we'll leave that and then we can have
another 40 odd levels when we need it so
it's good to have this stored up just in
case I'm probably gonna die now and lose
all of them so what's next for the base
well I'm very quickly outgrowing this
hobbit hole it's a fantastic start and
there's only one or two more things that
I'd like to do but I think the first
thing we got to do is send a message to
Mumbo with our new system I I don't even
I don't even know what I'm gonna say now
I'm just gonna send him random rubbish
all the time
pesky bird I do hope that he enjoys my
little presents off you go
oh he's gonna have so much junk mail
he's gonna regret letting that happen so
I've cleared up this space because later
on I would like to fill this up with
some sort of super smelter because I am
finding that there's some things that I
want to do like loads and loads of sand
and I just don't have the facilities but
overall The Hobbit hole is coming
together really really nicely now
outside you did see that I had been
working on this now this is for a very
specific reason I actually need to get
my hands on just a few villagers not a
full-on trading haul but I just need a
couple so that I can get some very
specific items so we need to transport
two villagers all the way over here but
first i'm going to make them a quick
place to live somewhere that fits in
with the hobbit hole it's you know gonna
be quite nice and then we've got to go
and get them so let's quickly finish off
this build no no
uh yeah I'll uh I'll uh I'm gonna
time-lapse this and I'll be right back
[Music]
this should do the trick there's plenty
of space within this sort of greenhouse
type thing that I've made to see what
all the villagers are up to there'll be
enough space for the beds and I've got
enough of these little pocket holes for
them to be able to be traded with now
the actual issue I have to solve is
getting the villagers here and mumbo's
kindly said I can borrow some but
they're all the way that way and I've
counted it's about 900 blocks yeah let
me repeat that 900. so I've crafted up a
bunch of rails and we're gonna do this
the old-fashioned way you can do this by
boat or by rail I figured the path of
least resistance is the rails so
unbelievably and I mean this is really
excessive we need to take this rail and
take it all the way over to wherever
mumbo's made here's little iron farm
all right so oh man
here we go
[Music]
it's there is there I I can't believe I
actually had enough rails to get here
and we have arrived and they're waiting
for me now I've never done this before
so I have no idea if this actually works
this is like such an old school method
of transporting instead of powering this
all with redstone uh power rails what
I'm hoping to do is just get one of
these guys into a minecart and there we
go and then what I'm hoping to do is
literally just power one of these and
watch it go I don't know how this works
though will it Power It Up the oh my
goodness
this is so much easier well he's off
he's off he's properly off he's picking
up some speed all right bye villager
number one oh dear all right let's send
the other ones along with him
[Music]
thank you
that went a little bit more smoothly
than I thought it would to be honest
with you not bad at all we've got all of
our villagers here safe and sound for
the most part we just need to uh
and and they've all become unemployed
this is absolutely perfect we need to
install just a very quick food dispenser
that like guinea pigs in here oh dear uh
so right I need to get rid of them
without hurting them oh no don't please
don't they're gonna try and leave
immediately so that's not gonna happen
and now we feed them bread
I need to put down the beds we could do
like a bunk bed system or we can just uh
just put them all in a line like this
and then all we gotta do is uh kind of
get them to to you know make more
Villages yeah take the bread more bread
more bread for you share the bread share
the bread now what I'm not really sure
what they're doing they're like food
food from above
hey hey it's a it's the Miracle of Life
okay we're definitely doing the right
thing sweet okay next stage do we want
to get rid of this
or is this a very easy way to get to the
the Villager breeder if I need to I'll
leave this up just for a little while
longer just in case I need it
but what I am going to need is a heck of
a lot more bread welcome to the world
little one the gods give us bread
I need somewhere with a bit more space
so I can grow more wheat because I
haven't really been preparing for this
moment that well honestly I didn't
expect it to be that easy to get them
here this track took like 10 minutes and
then it was a couple of minutes for them
to get back things never go this
smoothly on Minecraft not for me
maybe I'm getting better at the game
I need to get my villager numbers up hey
look he's got a little
jump on why aren't you guys jungle
villagers that's so cute I need more
beds I need more bread that should do
for at least a little while that will
help with the situation one of them
should
become a uh a dude no no no no
wrong one hey why didn't that work
that's weird
why did now why did that work while I
was standing on it
foreign what I don't know how that I
didn't do anything there everything I
know about Redstone just went out the
door did seriously that block make a
difference
no all right well whatever I guess let's
see what this guy is willing to give me
we're getting some emeralds built up
this is excellent oh oh
no trading with it Lux I forgot that
trading locks for I'm a full oh I forgot
I just realized that when you trade it
locks them it locks them in and that's
it job done forever so yeah I messed
that guy up let's see about him he wants
Flame
all right I'm gonna cycle through these
villagers and I'm gonna keep giving them
bread and I'm gonna see where we get to
on this whole thing uh I'm quickly
learning a lot about villagers I
honestly didn't I've never done this
before not properly I've only used them
for trading with the carrots and such so
I've now learned that they uh they just
frequently decide to check oh feather
falling four isn't not bad it's very
expensive mainly because I punched a
villager or two I think I might lock
that in and also the children have
escaped and they're playing all over
their house but when it's night time
they all go in they all go into bed it's
actually really really cute so I don't
know whether I should leave this in they
can just uh when when the Sun goes down
all the kids have to go in uh back home
he doesn't he doesn't seem to want you
know what Villages are such a pain I
might ask Mumbo what he thinks can he I
might need to ask for a little bit of
help Mumbo how do villagers work asking
for
remember how The Villages work now I
don't want him to think I'm silly saying
asking for a friend
tell you what I'm just gonna use this
that he sent me Mumbo how do Villages
work asking for a friend I think he's
just sending me junk because I sent I
sent him some junk mail oh
no it's not it's a sapling but it's got
It's got coordinates on it maybe mumbo's
got a present for me
anyway Mumbo had a villagers work asking
for a friend there we go and off it goes
I love this I seriously seriously love
this messaging system that we've got
going on but now oh this this is opened
a whole new bag of worms okay
mystery coordinates I need to prepare
what am I gonna wear what am I gonna
wear
I mean one of those situations where I
can't be bothered this is where my
storage system starts to go I need that
this is where my storage system starts
going to to heck actually because I I
end up getting lazy and then this
happens
um this is how chest monsters start
alrighty then let's see if you've
decided to change your attitude no you
have not
all right well let's follow these
coordinates wait where are they uh no
this direction and that direction
follow the random saplings instructions
this is very unlike Mumbo I can't wait
to get my hands on some elytra it's so
painful to travel through the jungle
honestly we're getting pretty close now
uh minus seven to seven six two
this is huge uh we've gone okay I don't
think this is it I'm about 300 blocks
away but what on Earth is this gigantic
thing what is this enormous structure
all made out of logs
oh my goodness
this scares me a little bit people are
already starting on their Mega bases I
haven't even finished my Hobbit Hole
pesky bird I've got I've totally gone
the wrong way why is it so hard to
follow coordinates now I'm just terrible
I'm meant to be here
as he sent me on a wild goose chase is
this his idea of a joke just send me
somewhere where there's oh pesky bird I
don't know what I'm supposed to be
finding here a jungle temple nothing
this has already been completely taken
it can't be this this has already been
ransacked unless this is meant to be it
I must have gotten something wrong here
just a couple more it must be nearly
there seven six two and oh
oh oh finally this is buried so deep in
the jungle okay is there any
instructions for me what is that
what is that
there's machinery
that looks fancy that looks really fancy
what have we got here put that there so
this is hold on let me just double check
I'm not messing minus seven six two yeah
this is definitely the spot what am I
supposed to do what am I supposed to do
geez oh that just passed straight
through my head
I'm scared is there a bed here is there
a bed here
is there a bed
is her in bed
is there a bed here so what am I
supposed to do
can I eat two cookies I'm gonna eat both
cookies oh where's the bed though
there's a Hermit challenges I don't know
what mumbo's on
is there a Bed initiation
[Laughter]
what initiation hermit challenges what
what is that what what even
what even is that
did I do something wrong did I do the
thing right did I win did I win the game
what is this please explain
please explain
I gotta I I'm gonna have to hop into a
call I shall initiation I shall
a bit challenges
what is this what is this insanity
Mumbo can you please explain
hermit challenges initiation
congratulations dude you're in have a
challenge this initiation you did it
nicely done no you're in you're in um
you initiated perfect that was a
Flawless initiation before you hit the
Bell you set fires to the thing really
nicely you did it in a slightly
different order you've eaten both
cookies
super initiated did you put you put some
coordinates down and went here and you
had some cookies like did you seriously
expect me not to eat the cookies well no
that was the kind of the pot I mean I I
kind of thought if I just gave you some
coordinates you would make your way
there I then knew that if I if I put
some buttons on things including some
cookies in the mix uh you know hermit
challenges initiation
so I won the challenge I won the hermit
challenge no no no not at all in fact
the challenges have just begun my friend
and because you ate both cookies you're
now in for life there's definitely no
leaving most people kind of have a
slight leaving cause but you have twice
as much
this wasn't the challenge no no no no of
course not dude of course not you see
these three pieces of paper right here
what you need to do is you need to write
out three challenges for me right I'm
gonna write out three challenges for you
and then we do the old Switcheroo I
chuck mine into that dropper you Chuck
yours into this dropper we hit the
buttons and hermit challenges hermit
challenges
helmet challenges
okay share with me hermit challenges
what kind of anything
anything what kind of anything exactly
uh
hermit challenge is let's do it cool all
right I'm feeling good I'm feeling good
Anvil's up at the top get busy get to it
I have no idea what to even write
but
[Laughter]
look I know you're new here okay oh now
you're tripling it yeah
so I no you're not supposed to know
right so I'm type this secretly yeah
yeah yeah yeah in fact you know what
I'll turn my back I'll walk behind this
rock over here and uh yeah we can we can
get back to talking terms in like a
couple minutes once we've sorted out our
challenges
I'm only going to show the audience here
Mumbo what you've got you got this one
uh this one and this one I have no idea
if these are good challenges or not but
uh good luck with that all challenges
are good challenges and hermit
challenges my friend
all right okay so you've put your three
in yeah yeah yeah are you ready to are
you ready for your first challenge of
hermit challenges yeah like yeah okay
okay three two one oh
I don't even want to look I don't even
want to look
good low
okay that was the first listen that was
the first one I did because I had no
idea what I was supposed to be doing I
take it back but when I said that
there's no such thing as a bad challenge
in Hermit challenges this is a
ton of this
all right what challenge did you get
this what you're feeling right now with
get good is how I felt when you made me
come here right okay that makes sense
that makes sense all right what channel
did you get okay okay okay steel front
doors for entire season
still front doors like everyone's house
door yeah yeah uh everyone's front door
yeah like do I have to do that yeah for
the whole season for the whole season
yeah the whole season dude nobody's
allowed a front door
you have to be the one that takes all
their front doors
you are joking I don't know if I can do
this what happens if I don't do this can
I just leave can I just no no no no no
no no okay fine if you don't want to do
it all right then what you really don't
want to do is this
what did you do did you just burn it
what yeah
say I can I can forfeit it by throwing
it in the fire no no I said if you don't
want to do it what you really don't want
to do is this I threw it in saying I've
accepted the challenge you oh no don't
listen
I just said dude
you've now got to remove doors for the
whole season too
so such nonsense fantastic well I look
forward to seeing well actually I've got
a front door so if anything I'm a little
bit upset that I really like my front
door but I feel it's going to go missing
at some point in the near future and can
never come back
one question okay yeah yeah do I do that
does everyone know or do I keep this a
secret I mean that's entirely up to you
but yeah I think if they know that
you're the one that's steaming all their
front doors No One's Gonna like you so I
personally would keep this between you
and me you know
anyway how many challenges
congratulations on your initiation dude
I'll see you in the next episode we can
compare progress and things obviously
you know I mean I'm gonna be honest you
won't have completed your challenge by
the next episode we might have to meet
up at the end of the season and discuss
how well you've managed to do but I want
to see at least some evidence that
you've uh that you've done some door
removal fantastic dude it's been nice
seeing you as always uh and um yeah I'll
I'll come back when I'm good I guess oh
yeah get my get get good what just
happened here I'm genuinely not quite
sure
what just happened
do we I mean I'm now faced with a choice
I either steal everyone's door secretly
and hide it
um for the rest of the season no less
oh I don't
or I don't yeah I think this is mine
[Laughter]
I think we got our first door of course
we're gonna do it
our reputation as a Hermit is on the
line here we're gonna need somewhere to
store all of these doors past and future
oh and I also
have a little bit more of a trading
thing going on here and this is why
because I can get rid of all this rotten
flesh from my XP farm
so useful we should make a room I don't
know where this room's gonna be it
should be secret somehow
oh maybe it could be somewhere around
here okay yeah we're gonna make a secret
room for all of our stolen doors and
that's where we're gonna store them okay
guys this literally only works if you
don't tell people okay just don't tell
them don't tell the other Hermits what's
going on be on the challenge with me
we're gonna steal the doors and we're
not going to let anybody know I will
make this room pretty at some point but
for now
we have got our first door
good times with scars
so bye bye door
I will be back with some more friends
for you but I will need an elytra to
take this even further because I'll be
honest I don't know where everyone's
base is and it's gonna be difficult if
you're just traveling but
I think I've got another message here or
maybe I didn't send it off no no but
I I asked him I asked him if he if he
knew how villagers were he said nobody
knows uh that's good to know this
messaging system's amazing
okay so I think that's all we're gonna
have time for today but my goodness did
did we actually get some things done
we've got our first ever trading haul
but you know the design of this is
actually pretty foolish because I've
only got three villagers spaces so I
think I will uh retrofit this so that I
can use the back for more villagers
anything anything anything nope nope
nothing good so I'm afraid that's it for
today's video thank you very very much
for watching this season has been
absolutely amazing so far and I can't
wait to see where we go next permit
challenges whose door should we get next
you decide tell me in the comments good
bye